黑帮天使 前情提要
Previously onThe Mob Doctor
只要你还在芝加哥，你就欠我的，这就是咱们的协议
As long as you're in Chicago,
I own you. That's the deal.
你在这干吗？
What are you doing here?
是你杀了我爸爸吗？
Did you kill my dad?
我发誓不是我干的
I swear to you I did not kill your father.
这孙子是谁呀？
Who the hell is this guy?
不是孙子，是儿子，爸爸
It's me, dad.
你想干吗？
What do you need?
我欠诺加莱斯·卡特尔的债
The money I borrowed belongs to the Nogales Cartel.
你惹大麻烦了
You're in a lot of trouble.
我跟卡特尔说了
I floated the message to the cartel
你愿意把卢克的债还上
that you're willing to pay off Luke's debt.
你还有事瞒着我，艾尔
There's something you're not telling me, Al.
他们已经开始报复行动了
They've already taken punitive measures.
他们雇了一个杀手来杀卢克
They've ordered a hit on Luke.
帕拉特尼骗了咱们，卡特尔根本没打算休战
Trapani lied about the cartel.There is no truce.
帕拉特尼根本就没跟他们说你要还上卢克的债
Trapani never even passed on your offer to pay Luke's debt.
如果他们知道你没事先打招呼就杀了他们的手下
If they find out you killed their man
这事很快就会难以控制了
without trying to negotiate,this is going to get ugly fast.
康斯坦丁在哪？
Where's Constantine?
救命！
Help!
来人啊！
Somebody, help!
救命！
Help!!
看着点后边儿，都躲开
- Watch your back.- Get out of the way.
58岁，男性
58-year-old male,
多处枪伤，昏迷
multiple gunshot wounds and unresponsive.
行了，哥儿几个，我们就在这接管了
All right, this is where we take over, folks.
剩下的你们不用管了
We'll take it from here.
他的血压降到87了
He's hypotensive to 87 systolic.
血肿扩大，肯定是颈动脉破裂
Expanding hematoma.Must have nicked the carotid.
血压降到55了
Pressure's down to 55.
得赶紧把动脉包扎起来
We need to tie off his artery right now.
三，二，一，走你
Move him. 3, 2, 1.
挂两个氧气袋……抽吸器
Hang two bags... O-neg.Suction.
54岁，女性，大腿和肩部枪伤
54-year-old female with gunshot wounds to the thigh and shoulder.
心跳130，昏迷指数6
Heart rate's 130.GCS is 6.
我马上回来，你们接手
Be right back.Take over.
格蕾丝。这是我母亲
- Grace.- It's my mom.
她失血两公升，B型阳性血
She's lost at least 2 liters of blood... B-positive.
周期性昏迷
Recurrent loss of consciousness.
行了，你别管了
All right, stop.
首先，我们得把她抬到病床上绑好
First, we got to move her,get her hooked up.
三，二，一，走你
On my count.3, 2, 1.
你找我？
I got your page.
鲁滨逊大夫，德芙琳夫人现在归你负责
Dr. Robinson,Mrs. Devlin is your patient.
她的胸部和大腿中了枪，你需要约什么检查？
She got bullet wounds to her chest and thigh.What do you want to order?
胸部，臀部和股骨部的X光片
Chest, hip, and femur films.
交叉备血四个单位，准备手术
Type and cross for four and prep an O.R.
星星啊，妈妈-你去洗洗手吧
- Come on, mom.- You need to get cleaned up.
不，我得陪着她-你别跟这裹乱了
- No, I'm not gonna leave her.- You need to go.
警察还想找你了解情况呢
I'm sure the police want to talk to you.
现在，这才是你救你妈妈的方式
Right now,this is how you help your mom.
我们得把他送到超声波检查室去，扩张他的颈动脉
We need to get him to the I.R.,stent his carotid.
这一夜会很漫长的
Gonna be a long night.
借过，大夫，我们得翻一下床单
Excuse me, doctor. I need you to sign the run sheet.
清理完了
Clear here.
包扎吧
Pack the gauze.
把手术刀递给我
Scalpel.
内特，是我啊
Nate, it's me.
格蕾丝
Grace.
有人在面包房开枪
Somebody shot up the bakery.
什么？这简直就是大屠杀
What? It was like a fricking massacre.
格斯，吉尔，斯塔沃斯全都死了
Gus, Gio, Stavos...They're all dead.
你怎么拿着康斯坦丁的手机？
Why are you answering Constantine's phone?
他现在在医院呢，妈妈也在这
He's here at the hospital.So is mom.
妈？
Mom?
有人开着车从面包房门口经过
There was a drive-by at the house.
他们俩都中枪了
They were both hit.
咱妈正要动手术呢，你赶紧过来吧
Mom is going into surgery.You need to get here.
我这就去
I'm on my way.
德芙琳大夫？
Dr. Devlin?
约克探员
Agent York.
令堂的事我很难过
I'm sorry to hear about your mother.
护理人员告诉我
I spoke to the paramedics.
枪击发生的时候你在现场，看见凶手了吗？
He said you were there when she was shot. Did you see anything?
没有，我当时在屋里
No, I-I was inside.
我听见枪声就跑出来了
I heard gunshots,and then I-I raced outside.
你有没有听见有车开走的声音
Did you see or hear a car speeding away,
或者别的什么能协助调查的线索？
anything that could help the investigation?
没有了，很抱歉我得走了
No, I'm sorry.I need to go.
德芙琳大夫，我们认为康斯坦丁
Dr. Devlin, we believe that Constantine Alexander
就是他们的袭击目标
was the target.
在他中枪之前一小时
An hour before he was shot,
至少有四个他的手下在他的店里被杀
at least four of his men were killed at his workplace.
貌似凶手在到处找他
It seems the shooter was looking for him,
而且是他的一个手下人把你家的地址泄露给凶手的
and one of his own men pointed him to your house.
我，我真的……
I-I really...
我知道你在治疗亚历山大先生的糖尿病
I understand you manage Mr. Alexander's diabetes.
对，没错
Yeah, that's right.
他有没有说过在个人或者在生意上
Had he mentioned if anyone had threatened him,
受到什么人的威胁
either personally or professionally?
没有
No.
我需要你配合我的工作
I need your cooperation here.
我们里在一起的时候，我们说的都是
Wh-when we're together, we talk about
他的血糖指数和他的饮食
his blood sugar levels and his diet.
就这些
That's it.
你弟弟呢？
What about your brother Nate?
他怎么了？
What about him?
众所周知康斯坦丁把他收在帐下当小弟
We both know Constantine took Nate under his wing.
我妈正在准备做手术
My mother is being prepped for surgery right now.
你能别跟这儿烦我吗？
Will you excuse me?
抽吸器
Suction.
股骨头末端破裂
Bone fractured distal to the greater trochanter.
斜口钳
Side biter.
格蕾丝
Grace.
你弟弟来了
Your brother's here.
咱妈怎么样了？
How's your mom?
哦，输了四个单位的血
Well, they transfused four units,
但是血压还是不稳定
but, uh,pressure's still borderline.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
大夫们正在抢救呢
The doctors are repairing the damage,
但是大出血还是没止住
but the bleeding is still a problem.
她有危险吗？
Is she gonna be okay?
我不知道
I don't know.
黑帮天使 第一季 第十三集 生或死（本季终）
The Mob Doctor 01x13 Life And Death
嘿
Hey.
手术怎么这么长时间，怎么回事？
That took longer than it should have. What happened?
要不是你当时在那
I mean,if you hadn't been there,
她可能都坚持不了这么久
she probably wouldn't have made it this far.
你控制住了她的大出血
You really slowed the blood loss.
她还没脱离危险
She's in critical condition.
她的股动脉被打穿了
Her femoral artery was punctured.
我们修复了骨折和大动脉
We stabilized the fractures and repaired the artery.
这很好啊
Well, that all sounds good.
是啊，不过这么重的伤
Yeah, it's just, with this kind of injury,
术后24小时都是危险期
the 24 hours after surgery are pretty critical.
在她脱离危险之前我都在医院守着
I'm not leaving the hospital until she's stable.
如果你有什么需要就找我
If you need anything, I'm here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你就说这有多讽刺吧？
It's ironic, isn't it?
什么呀？
What is?
我们正在努力抢救一个
The two of us doing all this work
尽人皆知的杀手
to save the life of a known killer.
说说吧，怎回事，大夫
Don't hold back, doctor.
这个人在监狱里呆了好多年
This man spent years in prison,
浪费了成千上万纳税人的钱
cost taxpayers hundreds of thousands of dollars.
现在他出狱了，谁知道他在搞什么勾当呢？
Now that he's out, who knows what he's up to?
我猜他肯定不会是卖圣经的
My guess...he's not selling bibles.
康斯坦丁·亚历山大是我们的病人
Constantine Alexander is our patient,
他现在处于病危状态
and he's in critical condition.
我们的职责是把他救活
Our job is to get him out of it alive.
废话，我又没说不救
Of course.I wasn't suggesting otherwise.
我只是就事论事
I was merely pondering the reality...
积点口德吧
Watch your catheter.
别给自己找麻烦
You don't want to break through the wall.
就是这儿
It's in position.
展开扩充器
Deploying the stent.
行了，支架已经安好了
All right.Stent's in good position.
出血止住了
Bleeding is stopped.
当然了，我止不住老去想
Of course,I can't help but wonder
他的枪伤对我们医院整体形象的影响
how his shooting reflects on our hospital.
你什么意思？
Excuse me?
你知道他是在哪挨的枪子么？
Our patient was found
德芙琳大夫的家门口
shot on the doorstep of Dr. Devlin's home.
我没必要跟你说这些
I don't have to spell it out for you.
是啊，没必要
No, you don't.
但是也许你应该
But perhaps you should find a hospital
找一家大家都爱传八卦的医院去工作
where the doctors are more to your liking.
现在这事大伙都议论开了
I'm just saying what everyone else is thinking.
那你就不要在瞎传这事了
And I think you've done enough pondering for the day.
是诺拉加斯·卡特尔的人干的吗？
The Nogales Cartel...that's who shot mom?
我觉得是
I think so.
老康打死了来刺杀卢克的杀手
Constantine killed their guy after he came after Luke.
卢克？-老康的儿子
- Luke?- Constantine's son.
是么
Right.
所以这是在报复老康？
So going after Constantine was payback?
看样子是
Looks like it.
老康到咱家来干吗？你知道吗？
Constantine stopped by our house. Do you know why?
行了，你得离开这
All right, you got to stay away from him.
刚才有个FBI特工来过
An FBI agent was just here
问起他的事
asking me questions about him,
而且他还问我关于你的情况
and then he asked me about you.
我？
Me?
他们盯上了老康的组织
Yeah, they're keep tabs on his organization,
这里还包括咱俩
including me and you.
格蕾丝
Grace.
她怎么样了？
How's she doing?
没什么变化
The same.
康斯坦丁检查完了
Constantine made it through I.R.
现在准备去做手术了
He's being prepped for the O.R. now.
谢谢
Thanks.
要是她醒过来或者有任何别的事
You text me if anything changes...
你就呼我
If she wakes up, anything?
你妈怎么样了？
Is your mom okay?
我想参加亚历山大的手术
I'd like to scrub in on Mr. Alexander.
怀特医生，我不能袖手旁观
Dr. White,I can't just do nothing.
我理解
I understand.
但是今天不行，格蕾丝
But not today, Grace.
这个人是在你们家门口被开枪打伤的
This man was shot on your doorstep.
你们俩还认识
You two know each other.
我是他的私人医生
I'm his doctor.
他的私人医生？
His doctor?
我负责治疗他的糖尿病
I treat his diabetes.
所以我觉得
It only makes sense that
我参与他的手术比较合理
I'm involved in his treatment here.
就算是我同意了，虽然我并不打算同意
Only if I were to okay it,which I'm not gonna do.
你觉得我对你总是神秘消失
You think I don't notice
还有你的特殊病人
all your mysterious disappearances
会没有察觉吗？
and your unusual patients?
我那是因为关心你，
I turn a blind eye because I care about you
才会睁一只眼闭一只眼不闻不问的
and it was easier not to ask questions.
现在你这些事全院都知道了
Now that your life has so publicly
谣言满天飞
found its way into my hospital, my O.R.,
我就再也不能让你再参加手术了
I can't allow it.
让你再参加手术了
Not anymore.
康斯坦丁·亚历山大是我的病人
Constantine Alexander is my patient.
你不要插手
You'll stay away from him.
我听说令堂有好转了
I heard your mother's in recovery.
真是个好消息
That's great news.
你谁呀？
Thanks?
内特，你和我都想
Nate, you and I want the same thing...
抓住杀害你妈妈的凶手
To catch whoever shot your mom.
杀手可能和射杀康斯坦丁手下的那些人
It's probably the same person or persons
是同一拨人
who shot up Constantine Alexander's place.
你有什么线索吗？
Do you have any leads?
从这两个枪击案现场收集的子弹
The bullets we recovered from both crime scenes
都是军用阿奎拉9毫米口径的
are Aguila 9mm from Centurion Arms.
你知道谁会用这种枪吗？
You know who uses those?
不知道
No idea.
诺加莱斯·卡特尔
The Nogales Cartel.
从来没听说过
I never heard of them.
内特，我知道你为康斯坦丁工作
Nate, I know you work for Constantine.
绑架，保险诈骗
The blackmail, insurance scams,
勒索比尔森街上的酒吧
the extortion of the bars on Pilsen Street.
是啊，我听说你已经盯上我了
Yeah, I heard you were keeping tabs on me.
你听说？谁告诉你的？
You heard that? From who?
这不重要，你那些指控没有任何证据
It doesn't matter. You can't prove anything.
实际上，我有证据
Actually, I can.
这些指控都加起来够你坐20年牢的了
And it all adds up...20 years behind bars.
如果你能协助调查
If you help me with this investigation,
那些事我就全当不存在
it all goes away.
好好想想吧
Think about it.
格蕾丝，我一听到消息就赶过来了
Grace, I came soon as I heard.
你妈怎么样了？
How's your mom?
哦，她正在恢复中
Uh, she's in recovery.
老康头儿呢？
And Constantine?
正做手术呢
Surgery.
别担心，他会挺过来的
Don't you worry.He's gonna pull through.
他是条硬汉，我认识的人里命最硬的
He's a real tough guy. The toughest guy I know.
这点你比谁都清楚对吧？
But you know that better than anyone, huh?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
没事，格蕾丝，我知道他对你都干了些什么
It's okay, Grace.I know what he did for you.
等会，你说什么，他对我做什么了？
Sorry? What...What he did for me?
在你小时候保护你和你妈妈
To protect you and your mom when you were a kid.
康斯坦丁做事的时候我在场
I was there when Constantine took care of business...
又快又坚决
Quick, decisive.
你那游手好闲的爸爸根本就没想到
Your deadbeat dad never saw it coming.
如果你问我，后来他怎么对待你们的
If you ask me,after what he did to you guys,
我觉得是他运气太差了
I think he got off lucky.
你要坚定信念
You just keep the faith, Grace.
老康不会有事的
Constantine will be fine.
我回头再打给你好吧
I'll call you later, huh?
我只不过是个护士，我怎么知道枪击案的事儿呢？
I just work here. How would I know anything about the shooting?
你是德芙琳大夫的朋友
You're friends with Dr. Devlin.
我这人朋友就是多
I have a lot of friends.
好吧，我没什么朋友
Actually, I don't,
不过我觉得无所谓吧
but that doesn't really matter here.
听着
Look...
我知道格蕾丝是个好人
I know Grace is a good person
而且她仅仅与黑帮的边缘人物有关联
and she's only involved with the outfit on the periphery.
但是现在，她却犯糊涂了
But right now, she's not thinking clearly.
作为她的朋友，劝劝她回头是岸
As a friend,tell her to talk to me.
我为什么要这么做？
Why would I do that?
因为我即能保护她，也能把她抓起来
Because I can protect her or I can prosecute her.
金特罗小姐，帮我劝劝你的朋友吧
Ms. Quintero,help me help your friend.
我得回去干活去了
I got to get back to work.
还有一个事儿
Just one more question...
你知不知道格蕾丝和佛朗哥·里昂的事？
What can you tell me about Grace and Franco Leoni?
没什么可说的，他们俩都分手一年多了
There's nothing to tell.They broke up years ago.
这么说他们俩还好过
So they used to date.
感谢你的配合
The bureau appreciates your cooperation.
格蕾丝，我觉得我闯祸了
Grace, I think I screwed up.
FBI的人套我话
That FBI guy cornered me
问了我好多关于你的问题
and asked me a bunch of questions about you.
你都说什么了？
What did you say?
我提到你跟佛朗哥好过
I kind of mentioned you and Franco used to date.
话赶话我就被绕进去了，真对不起
He caught me off guard.I'm so sorry.
听着，嗯
Look, um...
甭管我出什么事了我都爱你
Whatever happens to me,just know that I love you
而且我从来都不会
and I-I never meant to
怀疑我们的友情
take your friendship for granted.
求你了，别这么说呀
Please, please,don't talk like that.
康斯坦丁还没出手术室呢？
Is Constantine out of surgery yet?
出来了，都一个多小时了，怎么了？
Yeah, about an hour ago.Why?
我得跟他谈谈
I-I just need to talk to him.
这是你现在最明智的选择吗？
Is that the smartest thing for you right now?
可能不是
Probably not.
朝我开枪的这个
The men who did this to me,
杀死我朋友的这个残酷杀手
the ones that murdered my friends in cold blood...
早晚会付出代价的
They're gonna pay for this.
这都是因为我
This all happened because of me.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不用自责
Don't blame yourself.
你是我儿子，要是再碰上这种事我还会这么做的
You're my son,and I would do it again.
过来，我跟你说点儿事儿
Come here.I want to tell you something.
格蕾丝
Grace.
嘿
Hi.
你是格蕾丝·德芙琳
You're Grace Devlin.
我是卢克
I'm Luke.
见到你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
哦，我能跟老康单独谈谈吗？
Uh, may I talk to Constantine alone?
令堂没事了吧？
So, is your mother all right?
她还没脱离危险
She's in critical condition.
别担心，她能挺过来
Don't worry...she's gonna pull through this.
她是个坚强的女人，相信我
She's a strong woman.Trust me.
为什么这么说，你是永远都这么有把握吗？
Why, 'cause you've always been so trustworthy?
你什么意思？
What does that mean?
你知道，我爸爸是个酒鬼
You know, my father was an abusive drunk.
他毁了我的家庭
He destroyed my family.
然后你现在比他还要变本加厉地来害我
And you have managed to hurt me more than he ever did.
你不能这么说，格蕾丝
You can't mean that, Grace.
艾尔·特拉帕尼刚才来了，他以为我知道呢
Al Trapani just came by.He thought I knew.
他说当时他就在旁边看着
He told me he was there when you did it.
看着什么？
When I did what?
看着你杀死我爸爸！
When you killed my father.
然后你就信了？
And you believe him?
你就装吧
Just for once be the man you pretend to be.
都说出来吧
Spit it out.
想说什么就都说出来吧
I mean, you got something to say, just get it out.
我六岁的时候看见你的车从我家门口开过去
I was 6 years old when I saw your car pull away,
我努力说服自己那不是你
and I convinced myself that it wasn't you.
你说这些都不对，格蕾丝
You got it all wrong, Grace.
我的天，别说了，别说了
Oh, my God. Stop it.Just stop.
我没有杀你的父亲，我也没法杀
I didn't kill your father.I couldn't have.
但是为什么？
And why is that?
实际上，你知道为什么
Deep down, you know why.
你妈妈永远都不想让你知道
Your mother,she never wanted you to know,
也许她有她的理由
maybe with good reason.
但是不管你爱我还是恨我
But love me or hate me,
我都是你的爸爸
I'm your father.
这就是为什么她不告诉你
That's the reason why
我昨天晚上去找你
I was at your house last night...
就是想告诉你这个事
To finally tell you.
亚历山大先生，你感觉怎么样？
Mr. Alexander...how are you feeling?
好多了，大夫
Better, doc.
德芙琳大夫，你在这干吗？
Dr. Devlin,why are you here?
他的手机，哦，落在急诊室了
His phone, um,dropped in the E.R.
我过来把手机给他
I was just returning it.
然后说再见
And saying goodbye.
啊
Ah.
妈
Ma.
妈Ma.
嘿
Hi.
Hey.
嘿，格蕾丝
Hey, Grace.
嗯
Hmm.
你感觉怎么样？
How you feeling?
我好多了，但是
I've been better, but...
我是个幸存者，知道吗
I'm a survivor...You know that.
妈-啊？
- Ma.- Huh?
康斯坦丁刚才跟我说了
Constantine just told me something...
关于你和他，还有我
About you and him...and me.
哦？
Oh?
他跟我说……
He told me that...
他跟我说他是我爸爸
He told me that he's my father.
是么，我觉得他肯定是被枪打坏了脑袋
Yeah, right. I mean, he probably hit his head when he got shot.
别骗我了-那不是真的
Come on.That's not true.
那是我跟艾伦结婚两年之后
I was married to Alan for two years.
他很粗鲁，我当时觉得很孤独
He was very cruel,and I was so lonely.
但是……
But...
当我发现我已经怀了你之后……
When I found out I was pregnant with you...
你骗了我爸？
You lied to dad?
我必须得瞒着他，不然他会把我们都杀了
I had to, Nate.He would have killed us.
你知道的
You know that.
他都死了好几年了，妈妈，你为什么后来不告诉我们？
He died years ago, mom.Why didn't you tell us after?
这种事怎么说呀？
H-how do you t-tell somebody something like that?
我不想伤害你，格蕾丝
I didn't want to hurt you, Grace.
你知道，当我发现他死了
You know,when I found him dead,
我，
I, uh...
我觉得是我的错
I thought something was wrong with me.
我是说，哪个六岁的女孩会希望
I mean,what 6-year-old girl is glad
自己的爸爸被谋杀呢？
when their father is murdered?
什么？
What?
然后现在我又发现，他根本就不是我的爸爸
And now I find out he's not even my dad.
哦，格蕾丝
Oh, Grace.
抱歉，我得出去待会
I'm sorry.I'm just gonna get some air.
我太……
I'm so...
格蕾丝，我太对不起你了
Grace, I'm so sorry.
你干得很棒，你就了我的命
Did a great job, doc.You saved my life.
我得伤怎么样？
So, how's it look?
颈动脉功能恢复了
The carotid stent is functional.
几个星期之后就能出院了
You should be out of here in a couple weeks.
我想跟你谈谈关于德芙琳大夫的事
I wanted to talk to you about Dr. Devlin.
好哇，说吧
Sure. Go ahead.
你会毁了她的事业的，或者比这更糟
You're gonna ruin her career... or worse.
我知道你是谁，也知道你是干什么的
I know who you are,I-I know what you do,
而且我也知道你接下来的……计划
and I-I know about your...arrangement.
这么说你知道我是谁
So you know who I am,
然后你就这么跟我说话？
and yet you talk to me like this?
你很关心格蕾丝对吗？
You care about Grace,don't you?
是啊，不用担心她，大夫
Well, don't worry about her, doc.
我不会让她出任何事的
I'm not gonna let anything happen to her.
最好的办法是
The only way that works
你离她远远的
is if you leave her the hell alone.
我待会再来给你检查
I'll be back to check on you later.
你好哇？
Hello?
格蕾丝？哦，谢天谢地
Grace? Oh, thank God.
弗朗哥，我以为你说……
Franco, I thought you said
咱俩这么打电话不太安全
it wasn't safe for us to contact each other.
没事，这是一次性的电话
Uh, it's a disposable phone.
我从新闻上听说汽车枪击案的事了
I heard about the drive-by.It's all over the news.
是啊，我妈和老康都中枪了，但是他们没死
Yeah, my mom and Constantine were hit, but they're alive.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我没受伤
I'm not hurt.
我不是这个意思，我是说，你没事吧？
That's not what I'm asking. Are you okay?
我有事
Not really.
听着，我想告诉你
Look, there's something you need to know.
约克探员来过了
Agent York was here,
绕世界打听
and he's been questioning everybody.
小罗告诉他咱俩好过
And Ro let it slip that we used to date.
这下糟了
That's not good.
你还能为我抵挡多久？
How long before he figures out you've been covering for me?
好吧，听我说，好吗？
All right, listen to me,all right?
现在，如果他再去找你
Now, if he comes to you,
你不能让他发现你在撒谎
you can't let him catch you in a lie.
你还记得那最有力的三个字吗？
You got to remember the three most powerful words...
不知道（我还以为是“我爱你”呢——译者注）
"I don't know."
说出来
Say it.
我不知道
I don't know.
很好
Good.
我顶不了多久
I can't handle this.
你能行
Yes, you can.
你肯定能行
Yes, you can, you just got to
只要过了今天就没事了，好吗？
focus on getting through today,all right?
好吧
Okay.
我想你了
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
你早就应该告诉我这些事
I should know these things.
我不想让这些事
I don't want any of this to change
改变你对我和格蕾丝的看法
the way you feel about me...about Grace.
可是阿兰是我爸爸对么？
Alan was my dad, though, right?
当然了
Of course he was.
哦
Oh.
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
格蕾丝也会原谅你的，不过得等她疯完了再说
And Grace will, too,when she's done freaking out.
行了，我去找找格蕾丝，顺便安慰安慰她
All right, I'm gonna go find Grace and calm her down.
妈？妈！你怎么了？
Mom? Mom! Mom, are you okay?
快叫医生来！快呀！救命啊！
Get a doctor!Help! Help!
来人啊，我妈快不行了！救命啊！
Someone, I need help!My mom needs help!
格蕾丝，你刚才上哪去了？
Grace, where have you been?!
他们把你妈的危险警报上升到蓝色了
They paged a code blue on your mom.
正在抢救呢
They're working on her now.
妈！
Mom!
把电击器给我。格蕾丝，别这样
Give me the paddles.Grace, stop.
我需要两安培的重碳酸盐。把电击器给我！
I need two amps of bicarb.Give me the paddles!
嘿，你要是给她做电击的话
Hey, she went from v-fib to asystole
她就会从心律失常到心脏停搏，然后再也不会有心跳了
and never had a rhythm after that.
你试过抗利尿激素了吗？
Did you try vasopressin?
她的脂肪栓塞没有疏通
She threw a lipid embolism.
我们一点办法都没有
There was nothing we could do.
太对不起了
I'm really sorry.
她死了
She's gone.
嘿
Hey.
我正找你呢
I've been looking for you.
我们当时正在聊天呢
We were just... talking.
然后……
And then...
就什么都完了
Out of nowhere...
有时候，当一根长骨头被砸碎了
Sometimes,when a long bone shatters,
它，哦
it, uh...
很多碎骨头片就会扩散到全身
It showers pieces of the marrow throughout the body.
有一片骨头就留在她的肺部
And one of those pieces got lodged in her lung.
这么说是他的医生搞砸了
So her doctors screwed up.
不是，只是这种事没那么容易预测，你知道吗？
No. It's just not that easy to predict, you know?
这就是为什么术后24小时是最关键的时间
That's why the 24 hours after surgery are so critical.
天呐，格蕾丝
God, Grace.
别说了
Shut up.
妈妈死了
Mom's dead.
内特
Nate...
我曾经对她恶语相向
The things I said to her were really ugly.
她临死之前都觉得我在恨他
And she died thinking that I hated her.
格蕾丝……妈妈知道你爱她
Grace...mom knew you loved her.
在妈妈临死之前
That's... that's what we were talking about,
我就是这么跟她说的
right before...
她知道你爱她，我保证她知道
She knew.I promise you... she knew.
我只是去照顾她
I just went after her.
你知道，我根本没想那么多
You know,I didn't think about it.
我当时太生气了
I just was so mad.
你有理由生气
You had a right to be angry.
我并不是生妈妈的气
I'm not angry at ma, though.
有些事我必须去做，知道吗？
There's something I have to do, okay?
格蕾丝
Grace...
你妈妈的事我感到很难过
I'm so sorry to hear about your mother.
我最不愿看到的
The last thing I would have ever wanted
就是丹妮拉受到伤害
was for Daniella to get hurt.
但她死了
Well, she was.
而且所有的这一切
And all of it,
这些牺牲，这些尸体
the blood and the...the bodies,
都是你造成的
it all goes back to you.
别这么说，求你，听我说
Don't do this.Please, just listen.
我试图让自己相信，你还是有好的一面
I let myself believe there was something good in you,
但是我错了
and I was wrong.
我要把我知道的所有事都告诉FBI
I'm gonna tell the FBI everything I know.
我无所谓，一切都结束了
I just don't care.It's over.
好吧
Fine.
如果你想这么干，我不会阻拦你的
I won't stop you if that's what you want to do.
但是斯塔沃斯昨天给我发了个短信
But just know Stavos left me this message yesterday.
你要是不把手机还给我，我就不知道他说了什么
I didn't get it until you gave me my phone.
听着
Listen.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
特拉帕尼骗了拉特尔，他们根本就没打算休战
Trapani lied about the cartel.
There is no truce.
特拉帕尼从来没把你的想还清卢克欠款的事告诉他
Trapani never even passed on your offer to pay Luke's debt.
如果他们发现
If they find out
你没实现商量就杀了他的手下
you killed their man without trying to negotiate,
这件事很快就会升级
this is going to get ugly fast.
他给我发这条信息一个小时之后
An hour after he sent me this message,
他和我半个帮派的成员都被枪杀了
he and half my crew were gunned down... executed.
是特拉帕尼陷害了我
It was Trapani who set me up.
他根本就没跟卡特尔交涉
He didn't negotiate with the cartel.
杀手是他派来的
He sent the cartel.
他为什么要这么干？
Why would he do that?
你说为什么？
Why do you think?
他看到了一个夺权的机会，而且他付诸行动了
He saw an opportunity to seize power, and he took it.
你知道为什么他跟你说我的事吗？
Why do you think he told you about me?
就是想挑拨我们之间的关系
Trying to drive a wedge between us.
格蕾丝，卡特尔的手下也许扣动了扳机
Grace, the cartel may have pulled the trigger,
但为你母亲的死负责的是艾尔特拉帕尼
but Al Trapani is the one who's responsible
应该是艾尔·特拉帕尼
for your mother's murder.
如果你想让流血事件停止，如果你想要讨回公道
And if you want the bloodshed to end and you want justice,
那么我们就应该联手把他拿下
then you and me are gonna have to take him down.
我应该怎么做？
What would I have to do?
不行，这么做太疯狂了
No way. That's insane.
你是唯一一个能绕过艾尔特拉帕尼去跟诺加莱斯·卡特尔说上话的人
You're the only one who can contact the Nogales cartel
去跟诺加莱斯·卡特尔说上话的人
without involving Al Trapani.
是啊，当然了，他们一定愿意听我的解释
Yeah, of course they'd like to hear from me,
这样他们就可以找到我然后杀了我
so they can find me and kill me.
我只想用你在迈阿密的那些关系
All I'm asking you to do is use your Miami contacts
帮我安排一个和迪亚哥·恩里克斯的会面
to set up a meeting between me and Tiago Enriquez.
他是卡特尔在芝加哥的得力助手
He's cartel's lieutenant here in Chicago.
你疯了吧，这家为什么要跟你见面呢？
This is crazy. Why do you think this guy will even meet you?
因为我是康斯坦丁的代言人
Because I'm authorized to speak for Constantine.
当然我还是他的女儿
'Cause I'm his daughter.
这么说你知道了
So you know.
你能帮我吗？
Will you make the call?
我只是一个破产的不动产经纪人
Grace, I'm just a real-estate guy who screwed up.
我甚至都不该来芝加哥。我还是个外科医生呢
-I shouldn't even be here.-And I'm a surgeon.
这事对咱俩来说都不怎么在行
We're both out of our element.
我求你帮我这个忙
I am asking you to help.
我怎么能拒绝我的姐姐呢？
How can I say no to my sister?
什么东西？
What's that?
格蕾丝·德芙琳的通话记录
Grace Devlin's phone records.
那这干吗？
So?
看上去你们俩比我想得还要亲密
Looks like you two are a lot closer than I thought.
直到你离开芝加哥一个月之前
Until you left town a month ago,
你们俩还每天通好几个电话
you spoke several times a day.
电话很频繁啊
The calls are highlighted.
她是老康的医生
She's Constantine's doctor.
获取她的信任，就可以从老康那获得情报
I was gaining her trust.She has his ear.
别操你大爷了，弗朗哥
Cut the crap, Franco.
你们俩好上了是吧？
You used to date.Isn't that right?
是的，好长时间了
Yeah, a long time ago.
你就一点没跟我提过这事？
You just failed to mention it?
我当时还不太确定
It wasn't relevant.
它结束了我的卧底生涯
It ended the day I was recruited.
你有没有告诉她，她被FBI调查了？
You told her she was being investigated, didn't you?
你骗了我，弗朗哥
You lied to me, Franco.
她不仅仅是康斯坦丁的医生
She's not just Constantine's doctor.
她受康斯坦丁保护
She's under his thumb,
并且帮他做事
and she aided and abetted outfit activity.
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，那就让我告诉你我得到的消息吧
Well, then,let me tell you what I know.
我知道你对德芙琳大夫仍然有感情
I know you still got the hots for Dr. Devlin
而且我还知道最近又和好了
and I know you two started up again recently.
她只是协助我调查而已
She helped me with my investigation. That's it.
那你怎么解释犯罪现场鉴定科
Then how do you explain CSU finding her fingerprints
在你的藏身处找到很多她的指纹
all over your safe house...
要知道，那可是局里在你离开之前
You know, the motel room the bureau set you up in
特意为你准备的房间
before you took off?
我要把你的事报告给总局领导
I'm reporting you to the Attorney General's office.
他们会提出控告的
They're gonna press charges.
把你的枪和警徽给我
I need your gun and your badge.
别再浪费时间去追查格蕾丝了
If you're going after Grace,you're wasting your time.
这么不是你说了算的
Well, that's not your call to make.
我去后边的停车场看了，他还没来
I checked the back parking lot.There's no sign of him.
他迟到了
He's late.
咱俩都别着急
We're not in a rush.
我跟他说咱们要报警的时候
When I told him we wanted to meet at the police station,
他挺不高兴的
he didn't seem too happy.
是啊，咱们得先保证自己的安全
Yeah, well, we need to be safe.
你确定他听了斯塔沃斯的留言了吗？
You're sure he listened to Stavos' message?
那就是他同意来这的原因
Yeah, it's the whole reason he agreed to meet.
来了
Here we go.
恩里克斯先生，我是格蕾丝·德芙琳
Mr. Enriquez,I'm Grace Devlin.
你是康斯坦丁·亚历山大的女儿？
Constantine Alexander's daughter?
对
That's right.
这傻逼是他儿子？
And this piece of crap is Constantine's son?
对
Yeah.
艾尔·特拉帕尼……
Al Trapani...
貌似我被他设了个套去打康斯坦丁
Seems he played me against Constantine.
你爸爸是不是跟我一样生气？
Is your father as pissed off as I am?
是的，所以我们才来找你
Yeah, that's why we're here.
你觉得我们应该怎么办？
What do you propose we do about it?
康斯坦丁不愿和你作对
Constantine is willing to forgo retaliation
并且把艾森豪威尔高速路的西边入口
and give you free access to
的生意给你
the West Side Eisenhower Expressway.
好几百万呢
It's worth millions.
那不归他管
It's not his to offer.
艾尔·特拉帕尼管着高速路呢
Al Trapani controls the expressway.
作为交换，你得同意休战
In exchange, you'll agree to a truce
还得把卢克的债给免了
and you'll forgive Luke's debt.
你可以把这笔账算到特拉帕尼身上去
You'll take the hit off of Luke,and you'll put it on Trapani.
康斯坦丁现在还在医院
And you're telling me Constantine's got enough juice
他有那么多精力处理西边的事儿吗？
to take over the West Side from his hospital bed?
他控制着市里大多数议员的选票
Well, he owns enough aldermen to shift city council votes.
他有足够的手下去处理那些
He's got enough soldiers on the street
阻挡他生意的人
to crush anyone who won't play ball.
而且警察也是他收买好了的
And the CPD will turn a blind eye,
会对这事睁一只眼闭一只眼的
thanks to every cop he's got in his pocket.
如果我同意了
If I agree to this
但是康斯坦丁没挺过来死了
and Constantine doesn't keep up his end,
我们会再回来找你们俩的
we'll come after the both of you.
明白了么
You understand?
我跟我爸爸跟你保证据对没问题
You have my father's word and mine.
行吧
It's done.
我还没说完呢
Not yet.
是你们谁杀的我妈？
Which one of you shot my mother?
现在我说完了
Now we're done.
要不要打点胰岛素？
Does the patient need Insulin?
不用，他的血糖指数不高，就打点镇静剂就行了
No, his sugar levels are fine.I just gave him a sedative.
我能单独跟他谈谈吗？
Can we have a moment, please?
当然了，大夫
Of course, doctor.
怎么了？
So, what happened?
我跟他们说了
It's done.
恩里克斯会处理特拉帕尼的
Enriquez will take care of Trapani
代价是高速公路的生意
in exchange for the Expressway,
卢克的帐也抹了
and Luke will get a free pass.
好
Okay.
这能让我们在下一次行动之前
That'll give us the breathing room we need
有个喘息的时间
until we're ready to make our move.
下一次行动是什么意思？
What do you mean,"ready to make our move"?
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
你就直接说吧
Why don't you tell me?
在枪击案之后，这笔交易会让卡特尔
After the ambush, the cartel...
拿走咱们所有的生意
they could have taken everything away from us.
我们得让他放松警惕
We had to trick them into a sense of security.
所有的战争都是骗局，格蕾丝
All war is deception, Grace.
而我们在跟卡特尔的这场战争绝对不能输
And a war with the cartel is one we can't lose.
但是我们没输是因为我们还没开始打
But we're not losing 'cause we're not fighting.
这就是咱们的交易
That's the deal we made.
没有交易
There is no deal.
从来就没有交易
There never was a deal.
这全都是手段，是迷惑敌人的
It's all a tactic, an illusion.
你利用我？
You used me?
你要是知道整个计划就不会帮我做事了
Well, if you knew the plan,you wouldn't have done it.
而且除了你之外，
And there is nobody that could have
没有人能完成这件事
pulled this off like you,Grace... nobody.
我一点都不想卷到这件事里边去
I don't want any part of this.
你根本没得选，你还不明白吗？
You don't have a choice.Don't you see?
你是我的女儿，咱们是一家人
You're my blood, my family.
我什么样你就什么样
What is in me is in you.
我困了
I'm tired now.
我得睡会儿
I need to rest.
我会动用我所有的力量来打这一仗的
I'm gonna need all my strength for the fight ahead.
内特
Nate.
格蕾丝
Grace.
老康怎样了？他没事吧？
How's Constantine? Is he okay?
嗯，他，他没事
Yeah, he's...He's doing good.
我能去看看吗？
Can I see him?
哦，他，他现在需要休息
Oh, he's...He needs his rest right now.
我退出
I'm done.
啊？
Yeah?
康斯坦丁，他的帮派
Constantine,the organization...
我再也不想跟他们扯上关系了
I don't want anything to do with it anymore.
你有什么打算？
What about you?
我早就想好了
I made my decision a long time ago.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
♪ Finger on the trigger, baby
♪ come on, take me down
♪ I drug your name across my wrist ♪
♪ just to hear the sound
♪ want to feel the metal,
hot, smoking on my lips ♪
♪ take me low and take me high
♪ I just need a hit
♪ let's melt into the shadows
until there's nothing left ♪
♪ my blood spreads like a fire
♪ with your breath
across my neck ♪
♪ I'm not looking for a lover
to be gentle through the night ♪
♪ won't you be my killer?
♪ Keep me in your sight
♪ bang, bang, bang
你想好了吗？
are you sure you're ready for this?
现在就咱们俩
It's you and me now.
墨西哥，我们来啦
Mexico, here we come.
==Thanks for watching! Subtitle translation by @godort ==